

Daniel A. Sánchez R.

Computer Engineer

Urb. La Trigaleña, Valencia, Carabobo, Venezuela

Birth Date: 24/03/1986 Phone.: (+58) 0412-7667976

Email: ingdanielsanchezve@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://ve.linkedin.com/in/ingdanielsanchezvzla

Skype: live:ing.danielsanchez

Summary

Computer engineer with a large web development and software engineering experience using LAMP and MEAN stacks, knowledge in responsive web site development, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript, Jquery, Ajax, AngularJS, BackboneJS, Underscore, Mustache, GruntJs, VueJs,NodeJs, MochaJs, ChaiJs, PHP, Laravel Framework, SQL, MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, Firebird, MongoDB Databases, Linux, GIT, SVN, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, LinkedIn, Pinterest, Mailchimp and PayU developers APIs, Web Services and RESTful APIs development, Test Driven Development TDD, Unit Testing, MVC software architecture pattern, Apache module implementation, Linux Server Administration (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS), SEO knowledges, PI-SQL, Application Development with Oracle Developer Suite 6, Visual Studio 6, Agile development methodologies XP and SCRUM.

Experience

Senior Frontend Developer

Cecropia Solutions – Reliq health technologies (Remote – Ontario, CA) 04/2018 –07/2018

- Using AngularJs for the frontend code the UI.
- Create perfect pixel UI from design.
- Consume RESTful Api from backend endpoints.
- Create ajax request to the server to query the data stored in the system database and render in the interface usign backend endpoints.
- Use differents Jquery libraries to render charts with patients measures data.
- Design Html templates usign css framework Twitter Bootstrap
- Usign Atlasian Jiira to manage the user history, comments and development requests.
- Usign Atlasian Confluence for tickets documentations.
- Usign Atlasian Bitbucket as store repositorie and Git as control version system for the project code.
- Usign SCRUM Agile methodology as software development methodology with sprint daily standup, sprint look ahead, sprint review and sprint retrospective meetings.

Cecropia Solutions – Berkery Noyes LLC (Remote – New York, USA) 07/2017 –03/2018

- Using Javascript libraries to code the bussines logic for the UI.
- Render Project Views using underscore templates.
- Fetching data from database and render in the system views.
- Use BackboneJS, jQuery libraries and Mustache templates for the application frontend code.
- Create Ajax request to the server to query the data stored in the system database and render to the interface.
- Use Javascript to Create Validations to prevent user data entry errors.
- Test-driven development (TDD) using ChaiJs and SinonJs to create unit tests to verify the developed code work properly.
- Use TreeJS to display user acquitions types listed in the differents listbox.
- Design views wireframe usign css framework Twitter Bootstrap.
- Usign Jiira to manage the user history, comments and development requests
- Usign Git as control version system for the project code.

Chief Technology Officer – CTO

Soy Empleo (Remote – Medellin, Colombia)

10/2015 - 09/2017

- Create Backlogs, User Histories and developments tasks accord to SCRUM methodoly.
- Manage and Lead Work of frontend, backend and testing teams.
- Implementing and software setup in Linux servers. (Apache, MySQL, PHP, NodeJs, NPM, Mongo, Supervisor, Git, Beanstalk).
- Implementing SEO strategies in the company web sites.
- MongoDB database (Install, Update and Database Administration, Database Management, Index Creation, Backups, Restores, Users Authentication, Database Modeling, Storage Engine Configuration).
- Implementing colaborative software development tools (Git, Trello, Google Drive, Slack, Zoom).
- Creating Database Models Collections.
- Linux servers Administration in Amazon Web Service EC2 instances (AWS)
- Backend Software Development using Laravel Framework
- Frontend Software Development usign AngularJs and VueJs
- Test-driven development (TDD) using PHPUnit to create unit tests to verify the developed code work properly.
- UI design using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Fontawesome, Glyphicons.

Full StackDeveloper

Octopus C.A. (Valencia, Venezuela)

09/2013 - 11/2015

- Development and implementing of backend scripts using PHP, Laravel, NodeJs.
- Integration with Facebook APIs, Twitter APIs, Instagram APIs and Pinterest APIs.
- MySQL (Database Administration, Database Management, Index Creation, Backups, Restores, Users Management, Database Modeling, Functions and store procedures develop).

- MongoDB (Install, Update and Database Administration, Database Management, Index Creation, Backups, Restores, Users Authentication, Database Modeling, Storage Engine Configuration).
- Implementing and configuration of software in Linux servers. (Apache, MySQL, PHP, NodeJs, NPM, Mongo, Supervisor, Git, Beanstalk).
- Implementing SEO strategies for the bussiness web sites.
- Development and implementing of frontend scripts using Jquery, Javascript, Angular, Blade, Mustache, Grunt.
- UI Development with HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Fontawesome, Glyphicons.

Development Analyst II

Valencia City Hall(Valencia, Venezuela)

01/2012 - 07/2014

- Development and maintenance of the Applications and Websites of the Valencia City Hall using LAMP stack technologies.
- Use jQuery to validate, create ajax requestand and add animations for the websites.
- Development and maintenance of the tax collection system of the Valencia City Hall using Oracle de Developer Suite (Forms y Reports).
- Development of SQL scripts, Database Modeling, Tables, Views, Functions and Procedures in Oracle using TOAD for Oracle.
- Development of modules and maintenance of the system of civilian register of the Valencia City Hall using Visual Basic 6, Crystal Reports, MySQL.

Technological Process Analyst II

Valencia City Hall(Valencia, Venezuela)

08/2008 - 01/2012

- Applications development using Oracle de Developer Suite (Forms y Reports).
- Web applications development using LAMP stack.
- Development with Visual Basic 6.
- MySQL Database Administration.

Skills	 ProjectsPlanning 	• Grunt	 Microsoft
	 Projects Manage 	 NodeJs 	Windows
	Html	 Underscore 	 Visual Basic 6.0
	• Css	 Mustache 	 PostgreSQL
	Javascript	Linux	 MongoDB
	JQuery	 Apache 	Toad
	 JQueryUI 	PHP	 Sublime Text
	 BackboneJs 	 Laravel 	 Facebook API
	Ajax	 MySQL 	Twitter API
	 AngularJs 	 SQL 	Instagram API
	VueJs	 Oracle 	 LinkedIn API
	AWS	 PI-SQL 	 Pinterest API
	 Google Cloud 	 Oracle 	 API Rest
	 Mongo Chef 	Developer	
		Suite	

Education

Computer Engineer

Valencia Technological Institute September 2009 – June 2012

Web Application Development Diplomature

Jose Antonio Paéz University September 2007 – April 2008

Technician in computer science

Valencia Technological Institute September 2002 – June 2008

Languages

Spanish

Mother Language

English
Fluent

Reading

French